<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog by Satyam</title>
    <link>https://stym06.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog by Satyam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:17:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://stym06.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Database From Scratch 💾</title>
      <link>https://stym06.github.io/posts/build-a-db-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 23:17:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stym06.github.io/posts/build-a-db-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Hey folks, This is the introductory chapter on a series of blogs on how you can build a database from scratch by yourself.
But Why? Why build a database, you ask? There&amp;rsquo;s plenty already. And I only care about the CRUD stuff.
Umm, I guess most of us treat a database as a black box and dump stuff into it. But we only care about some of it if we get a connection pool failure alert on our pager.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consistent Hashing #️⃣</title>
      <link>https://stym06.github.io/posts/consistent-hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 22:18:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stym06.github.io/posts/consistent-hashing/</guid>
      <description>The world works on distributed systems, and if there is one thing that is always happening is routing of requests. Be it how your Instagram posts go to that specific data-center or how the IPL matches being streamed are coming to us from which one of the global CDNs, all of this is a matter of effective choice of request-&amp;gt;server mapping essentially.
We have load balancers which do some of this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World 👋🌍</title>
      <link>https://stym06.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 22:18:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stym06.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is the first time I&amp;rsquo;m writing something on a blog of my own, guys. I must say that I never knew composing a blog using Markdown was really possible. I had set up so many blogging platforms over the years using every frontend and backend stuff I learned, but as Da Vinci had correctly said:
&amp;ldquo;Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication.&amp;rdquo;
So, here we are, I&amp;rsquo;m using this neat little static site generator called Hugo to build my blog finally.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
